Passion for technological excellence in developing web & desktop-based, mobile applications.

Solid working skills in Object Oriented Programming, worked in agile and waterfall model projects.

Ability to take ownership and manage multiple tasks according to their priorities, ability to learn and understand new domain knowledge and business processes quickly.

Experience in Banking, Healthcare & Retail domains and excellent debugging skills.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS:**

Programming & Scripting: C#.Net, VB.Net, Python, C, C++, R, JavaScript, Backbone.js, React.js

Web Technologies : ASP.Net, HTML, CSS, XML, Razor(C#)

IDE & Versioning Tools : Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, Anaconda, TFS, VSS, SVN, Bitbucket, Git, RStudio
Tools : SandCastle, Tableau, Fiddler, Postman, Tidal Job Scheduler, IVANS, Service Now, Splunk

Databases : MS SQL, Oracle SQL, MongoDB

### **EDUCATION:**

Master of Science – Computer Science - 2022 - Old Dominion University Bachelors – Electronics & Communication Engineering – 2007 – Anna University

#### WORK EXPERIENCE:

## Engineer Sr. | Anthem, Inc. VA

Dec 2015 - Current

Development & maintenance of Government Business Division - Member Billing. Finance, Cash Operations, Billing areas. Activities involve LOE estimation, impact analysis, application support, deployment & job maintenance Tools & Technologies: Microsoft Visual Studio IDE, .Net, Bitbucket, Git, MS SQL, Oracle SQL, SVN, Nuget, Facets, Nunits, QTests, Tidal Job scheduling and maintenance

# Associate - Projects | Ernst & Young, GA

Apr 2014 - Nov 2015

Develop Audit Tool for Future, which enables design and execution of audit in accordance to Global Auditing Methodology; it is a single page web application, which works in online, and offline mode.

Tools & Technologies: Backbone.js, React.js, RESTful and MVC Web API, OData, Entity & Document Framework, TFS

#### Associate - Projects | United Health Care Group, MN

Jan 2014 - Mar 2014

24\*7 Application maintenance for Life Disabilty & Stop Loss, Rating Services, Quoting Services, Product Services, Client Letters, Online Portals and its database to maintain 100 percent application uptime Incident, Problem & Ticket resolution, Defect fixing and enhancements, Technical specification & Documentation

# Associate - Projects | Total System Services, GA

Aug 2013 - Dec 2013

Dispute resolution and charge back case management application with development and maintenance ASP.Net application with JQuery and Web Services, Performance tuning with ANTS profiler and Integration testing

# Associate - Projects | Walmart, AR

Jul 2012 - Jul 2013

Ecommerce website order filling and processing application Windows application development, testing and maintenance

## Associate - Projects | Collective Brands, Inc., KS

Jul 2010 – Jun 2012

Enterprise CRM application for maintaing customer demographics, rewards, coupons, feedback, and promotions for enhancing sales

Web applications with WCF Services, testing and maintenance

## Associate - Projects | Ace Hardware, IL

Apr 2008 - Jun 2010

Warehouse Outbound scanning application for order processing Windows & Web applications with WCF Services, AS400, MS SQL and Job Control Language Development, enhancement, migration and defect fixing